<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 11:31:21 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 11:31:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3 2018 Programme</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The programme can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://indico.cern.ch/event/663264/timetable/#20180129&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event consists of &lt;em&gt;7 sessions&lt;/em&gt; in a single-track: &lt;em&gt;5 regular oral sessions&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em&gt;2 special-format sessions&lt;/em&gt;. In between sessions there will be plenty of time for discussions and networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this edition we added an exciting new session on &lt;em&gt;Cloud Infrastructure&amp;amp;Software Stacks for Data Science&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all regular sessions oral presentations are accepted. The number of slots is limited and not guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;user-voice-novel-applications&quot;&gt;User Voice: Novel Applications&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Format: prime time presentations, 25 minutes + 10 minutes QA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an increasing number of scientific-, engineering-, collaborative- and office applications closely integrated with CS3 services (cloud storage and file sync/share services). This session is designed for (power-)users of such novel applications to share their experience with synchronized-, online- and offline-storage: benefits and areas for improvement of CS3 services in their respective application domains. This session is an opportunity for service and technology providers to understand opportunities and new requirements but also shortcomings of existing CS3 implementations from the most important perspective: the one of the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application domain examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image collection, processing and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educational applications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scientific notebooks for data processing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaboration and communication in teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decision support systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem solving environments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data curation and publication workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scalable-storage-backends&quot;&gt;Scalable Storage Backends&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Format: oral presentations, 20 minutes + 5 minutes QA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-performance and cost-effective storage solutions are important to scale up and evolve synchronization services. The separation between the storage backend used for offering sync&amp;amp;share services and the ones for analytics is usually not desirable. This separation prevents the users to easily share algorithms and results; it also complicates data correlation and full-statistics access; ultimately hardware resources are not optimally used and managed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the storage track we call for contributions from innovative storage providers. Interesting storage systems should promote seamless integration with synchronization infrastructures. They should scale above many thousands of clients and have multi-PB storage capacity. To allow federating distinct storage resources, multi-site capabilities are quite important; cache capabilities to improve user experience and system resilience are also interesting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;synchronizationsharing-technology--research&quot;&gt;Synchronization/Sharing Technology &amp;amp; Research&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Type: oral presentations, 20 minutes + 5 minutes QA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a classic CS3 session to present technology, design, experimentation and research results relevant for development and operation of synchronization and sharing services. The topics include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;algorithms and protocols for file sync and sharing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sharing and metadata semantics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;data integrity, reliability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;conflict resolution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;network-aware design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;software QA hardening and resilience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;desktop and mobile integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;backup strategies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;monitoring tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;testing frameworks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;security frameworks and procedures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;new user interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;file-syncshare-products-for-home-lab-and-enterprise&quot;&gt;File Sync&amp;amp;Share Products for Home, Lab and Enterprise&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Format: oral presentations, 20 minutes + 5 minutes QA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this session software companies present their File Sync&amp;amp;Share products: latest releases, planned new feature and development roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past speakers included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nextcloud, Owncloud, Powerfolder, Pydio, Seafile, Syncany&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cloud-infrastructuresoftware-stacks-for-data-science&quot;&gt;Cloud Infrastructure&amp;amp;Software Stacks for Data Science&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Format: oral presentations, 20 minutes + 5 minutes QA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Classical networked storage systems typically accepted science data in bulk uploads, often after processing; as a consequence, stored data usually wasn’t &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; in the sense of &lt;em&gt;fresh from the instrument&lt;/em&gt;. Similarly, efforts at building Virtual Research Environments (VREs; essentially cloud-based science toolchains) haven’t seen great uptake, again because the tools are only useful if they have fresh data to operate on, and users typically do not good discipline at regular uploading of data taking runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, synched data stores hold what can be considered &lt;em&gt;live data&lt;/em&gt; – thereby offering the possibility of performing first-line scientific munging / workflow / analytics on the cloud platform, rather than on researchers’ desktops. This opens up interesting possibilities of transparent compute scaling, GPU compute, science package management etc. not normally available on researcher-managed (&lt;em&gt;desktop&lt;/em&gt;) platforms. This stream is intended to showcase such novel opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keywords:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Virtual Research Environments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Management and Workflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File Transfer &amp;amp; Distribution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Virtualization: Open Stack, Open Nebula&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Containers and Orchestration: Kubernetes, Mesos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analytics: Hadoop,Spark&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compute and Grid services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;special-format-sessions&quot;&gt;Special-format sessions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interoperability&quot;&gt;Interoperability&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Format and contributions: to be defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Session on Open Cloud Mesh (OCM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;site-reports&quot;&gt;Site reports&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a growing number of sync&amp;amp;share services deployed and operated in the CS3 community. This session is an opportunity to present current status and plans, user feedback as well as share operational experience: main issues and concerns for your service. This session will provide a &lt;em&gt;family photograph&lt;/em&gt; or a &lt;em&gt;map&lt;/em&gt; of all CS3 services in operation to give a clear and concise picture of the whole service community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Format:
A summary of all site reports will be presented by a session convener in one single presentation. There will be few selected lightning talks on service highlights. This will be followed by the plenary discussion involving all participants. Immediately after the discussions will continue around the posters in the lobby. The posters will be on display for the whole time of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How you can contribute:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You are asked to provide basic information about your service according to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://cernbox.cern.ch/index.php/s/MwDjy0UEwfOjG5z&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; By entering providing the information you will enter into the official CS3 contributor list.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You are entitled to prepare a poster which will be displayed at the venue.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Optionally, if you believe there is a particular highlight of your service, you may consider a 5 minutes lightning talk + 1 minute QA slot. The number of such slots is limited and not guaranteed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/programe</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/programe</guid>
        
        
            
        
            
            <category>en</category>
            
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for Abstracts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Workshop on Cloud Services for File Synchronisation and Sharing (CS3) 2018 will be held 29-31st of January in a historic city of Kraków.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;full-program-is-available-herehttpcs3cyfronetplblogprograme&quot;&gt;Full program is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/programe/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;presenters--who-will-speak-at-the-cs3-workstop&quot;&gt;Presenters – who will speak at the CS3 Workstop&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;institutions providing or planning innovative services for collaborative cloud storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developers (freelance, hired) or active researchers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;established companies and start-ups developing solutions or providing services for collaborative cloud storage (apps, tools, frameworks etc.)e (apps, tools, frameworks etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;projects proposing innovative ways to create/federate distributed user communities in the area of research, education and innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you belong to one of those groups you are cordially invited to submit a talk proposal (or a number of proposals). The programme committee assesses the proposals and selects the actual conference talks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;please-submit-your-proposals-herehttpsindicocernchevent663264&quot;&gt;Please submit your proposals &lt;a href=&quot;https://indico.cern.ch/event/663264/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadlines:&lt;/strong&gt; are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abstract submissions opens: September 1st 2017&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Registration opens: September 1st 2017&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abstract submission closes: &lt;s&gt;November 30st 2017&lt;/s&gt; extended to December 10th 2017&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accepted abstract notification: December 10st 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note:&lt;/strong&gt; The number of presentation slots is limited. Authors will be notified if their abstract was selected for presentation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;any-questions&quot;&gt;Any questions?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email organizers at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cs3-cyfronet2018@cern.ch&quot;&gt;cs3-cyfronet2018@cern.ch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/call-for-abstracts</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/call-for-abstracts</guid>
        
        
            
        
            
            <category>en</category>
            
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3 2018 Announced!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year event will take place in cultural capital of Poland - Kraków. Being a unique European city in Poland, Kraków come through World War II essentially undamaged, and its assembly of monuments has since been hailed as one of Europe’s most compelling by UNESCO. The city’s Old Town (Stare Miasto) swarms with visitors in summer, but retains an atmosphere of fin-de-siècle stateliness, its streets a cavalcade of churches and palaces. A university centre, Kraków has a tangible buzz of arty youthfulness and enjoys a dynamic nightlife. So take your time to a few days in one of the last hidden gems in the Europe in a company of experts and technical geeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So should you also be excited? Well yes… and here’s why!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attendance&lt;/strong&gt;: we’re expecting over 200 attendees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;: more than 24 hours cloud and file synchronization related technologies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: 29-31 of January, 3 days of talks and networking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue&lt;/strong&gt;: Department of Computer Science AGH&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programme&lt;/strong&gt;: in preparation, an important part will be given by the contributions (120 in the last editions) from academic, service providers and companies leading the field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/cs3-announced</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/cs3-announced</guid>
        
        
            
        
            
            <category>en</category>
            
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is the workshop about?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is focused on non-traditional working storage: Cloud Storage Services for File Synchronization and Sharing (CS3). Particular attention is given to scientific and engineering applications and environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full program is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/programe&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event history can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/road_to_krakow_cs3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RtEXM5H.png&quot; alt=&quot;communities&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cs3.surfsara.nl/site/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/board.png&quot; alt=&quot;communities&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/what-is-the-workshop-about</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/what-is-the-workshop-about</guid>
        
        
            
        
            
            <category>en</category>
            
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Road to CS3 Krakow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We will meet at the 4th Cloud Services for Synchronisation and Sharing (CS3) Conference in Krakow to review the state-of-the-art and share experiences about cloud storage services.  The community which gathered around the previous CS3 events includes users, service providers and developers of technological solutions. 
The initial trigger of this conference series (CERN Geneva, November 2014) was the perception of the importance within the research environment of storage services capable to synchronise, share and interact with growing data volumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second conference (ETH Zurich, January 2016) we witnessed a growing interest in a larger community and the first  prototypes of innovative non-traditional working storage: systems having at their centre synchronisation and sharing capabilities are natural candidates to host demanding data processing in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third event (SurfSARA Amsterdam, January 2017) confirmed these trends and attracted larger community of technology leaders and alongside a solid CS3 community which is now organising in proposing and executing innovative projects and proposing standardisation lines across different installations and technologies.
Large-scale synchronization and sharing capabilities are already challenging existing IT infrastructures in all areas, from security models to integration with compute resources. This situation calls for renewing computing infrastructures and the way research is done locally and across collaborating institutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in the past, the conference will maximise the opportunity to liaise with key actors of the community. We invite you to submit abstracts using the abstract submission page. Selected presentations (oral or poster) will be part of a Book of Abstracts to be published in the conference website (Book of Abstracts of last conferences are available online).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/road_to_krakow_cs3</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cs3.cyfronet.plhttp://cs3.cyfronet.pl/blog/road_to_krakow_cs3</guid>
        
        
            
        
            
            <category>en</category>
            
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
